Carson Bruce

View at carson.kiwi

I am passionate about creating simple and beautiful apps.

I plan and deliver throughout the entire software development process, from when a project is imagined to its released. I've worked on a number of large projects, demonstrating my experience through a range of roles.

My key attributes include: problem solving, speed and passion to learn, open mindedness, and being a team player.

I am an early adopter of JavaScript technologies, React, Angular, Node.js, and Express, embracing the continuing shift towards simpler and more agile systems and process.

I am at home working and sharing JavaScript along with all the technologies and processes it enables.

Get in touch at hello@carson.kiwi

Experience

Solnet

Aug 2012 - Now (5 years)

I started Solnet a week out from graduating kicking off the role in the delivery team of the company. I have gained experience with several high profile clients placed first as a front end developer along with other roles such as dev ops, api developer, automation testing, and ux. More recently in my time at Solnet I have been involved in mentoring team members in JavaScript tooling and practices through 1-on-1 catch ups and wider group presentations.

Take a look at the Projects section to see some of the work I've done with Solnet.

Research Project: Query Expansion

Nov 2011 - March 2012 (4 months)

My second research opportunity was offered by the supervisor of my honours project to further its final report towards an end goal of a published research paper. With some give and take from the wider Web Intelligence team at Victoria I managed to get the paper submitted and accepted to an Australasian Web Intelligence conference.

Research Project: Eye Gaze tracking

Nov 2010 - March 2011 (4 months)

I was awarded a research scholarship at the end of my 300 level university year. With support from my supervisor and his team, I contributed to development of an open source gaze tracking system helping it evolve to a level where it could benefit the university, saving an equivalent commercial product cost of \$10,000.

Cool Bananas

Nov 2009 - March 2010 (4 months)

Interning with a fellow student alongside a senior software engineer I worked on a project developing a prototype scripting parser and runtime for embedded systems. The experience helped cement my years study learning C, Agile processes, and testing practices. The project proved successful gaining further funding being developed into a commercial product.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Software Engineering, First Class Honours

Victoria University of Wellington

2007-2012

Projects

Lending and Onboarding

BNZ

Joined a team at BNZ to help in transforming their Lending and Onboarding systems aiming to improve the experience for customers, bank staff. This transformation was supported by a new way of delivery, promoting more modular systems design and implementation with supporting Platforms and Devops processes. I joined as a Front End developer, sharing lead for the implementation of two major applications and a component library.

- Pioneered application development seeing Angular 2 through its beta releases.
- Promoted and adapted a UI component library for the projects multiple applications.
- Guided Front End developers through best practices, process and tooling.
- Guided UI Integration testers through best practices, process and tooling.
- Followed and feed back into areas close to UI to ensure smoother transitions including UX, Platforms, Devops, and API.
- Involved in successfully delivering the systems first release.

Employment Agreement Builder

Ministry of Business and Innovation and Employment

Using EAB, small to medium businesses can step through the process of creating a new Employment agreement while learning about employment law with easy-to-digest content. The project exceeded its objectives and was built, tested, and delivered in three months.

- Practiced BDD and TDD ending up with a feature complete integration and unit test suite.
- Created and published a decoupled CMS component.
- Created a reusable data-driven forms solution reused for a second MBIE Policy builder application.
- · Sold a full stack JavaScript solution to architects.
- Implemented a Node.js micro services implementation handling 10x expected load.
- Implemented a CI environment that performed automated testing and releases a dozen times a day avoid any manual tasks.
- Pushed a docker solution bringing build and deployment time down to minutes rather than hours.

Online Banking

Westpac

I was part of a Westpac team to evolve their online banking experience, originally rolled in as an IBM Worklight consultant and dev ops engineer. I helped keep the project oiled by mediating communications between developers from API and Client teams. I improved automation in local, development, and test environments helping developers become more autonomous. After two months my role extended to technical lead of a team five large responsible for feature development in the middleware including client security.

- Presented and owned the solutions of several developer tooling and experience improvements.
- Technical leader and mentor of a team five large covering a wide spread of technologies and environments.
- Trusted as the gatekeeper of critical development and test environments relied on by a team 60 large.
- Implemented a JavaScript middleware framework that improved the abstraction and reliability of the middleware HTTP adapters.
- Implemented the security feature encompassing the client and middleware layers.
- · Presented a UX review noting several usability and performance improvements for the application.

NEON

NEON is Sky TV's entry into the New Zealand TV on demand market. Our project was responsible for implementing the Web client and the Web API supporting other NEON apps sitting on other platforms. My role was a front end developer with a close interest in the Web API and UX layers that my tasks depended on.

- Worked with the Front end team to implement an angular application within Liferay
- Designed REST API transforming PAAS data sources to support the multiple client layers
- · Presented UX and design alternatives to client.
- · Worked remotely for half the project.
- Managed my time effectively within a time pressured environment completing and communicating tasks to project managers.

Crew Forms

Air New Zealand

Crew forms was a heavily digital project looking to turn a paper based form into a mobile tablet-based solution. The experience of these forms was improved with the new technology and with a change in platform the forms were allowed to be reimagined through UX process to further better user experience rather than being a clone of the paper solution. I worked on the project in its second phase after its first release bringing in a couple of new features and polishing the first implementation.

- Polished the app correcting dozens of browser rendering bottlenecks resulting in a jank free hybrid solution.
- . Worked with UX and design team to best fit solutions with the technology stack.
- Extended the apps feature list and matching test coverage.
- Provided solutions bugs found within open source libraries

Name learning game

Private

We entered in a competition to imagine, design, and develop a proof of concept mobile gamification app in 3 days. The brief was to create an educational tool that would help staff learn the names of their clients. We were placed well in the competition winning the prize of placing in the company's evaluation panel for future projects followed shortly after with a winning proposal for a separate project.

- · Created a complete proof of concept application in 3 days.
- Succeeded in gaining a position on the client's project panel.
- Worked effectively with other JavaScript, UX and UI developers in parallel streams.

Interests

JavaScript	User Experience	Netball	Running
Cycling	Photography	Gaming	Sound systems
	Beer brewing	Stenciling	